charliehr.com 2017-06-09

# Charlie

### **CharlieHR : Privacy Policy**

_Updated: Thursday 21 st April 2016_

CharlieHR (" **We** ", “ **Us** ” and “ **Our** ”) remain fully committed to the protection of your and your Users’ privacy at all times. The information contained in this policy has been published to inform you of the way in which any personal data you provide us with or we collect from you will be used. We recommend that you read this information carefully in order to fully understand how we treat such personal data.

IF YOU DO NOT ACCEPT AND AGREE WITH OUR PRIVACY POLICY THEN YOU MUST NOT ACCESS OR USE CHARLIE OR THE SERVICE.

Please read this policy in conjunction with the [End User Licence Agreement for Charlie](http://www.charliehr.com/terms) (the “ **EULA** ”). When you access or use Charlie, you agree to our privacy policy and you consent to our collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal data as set out in this policy. Any capitalised terms not defined in this policy shall have the same meanings given to them in the EULA.

In accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 (the " **Act** "), it is our obligation to inform you that the data controller is Charlie OS Limited and we are registered with the UK Information Commissioner’s Office with registration number ZA170135.

PERSONAL DATA WE MAY OBTAIN FROM YOU

We may obtain and use the following data about you and your Users:

  * Any correspondence we have with you and your Users should you or your Users contact us
  * Data you or your Users provide when you fill out forms on our Website, including but not limited to data you provide when you register to become a user of the Service
  * Data and information you or your Users submit or upload to Charlie or the Service, including Client Data (which may include, among other things, dates of birth, residential addresses, names, email addresses, telephone numbers, National Insurance numbers, bank details, passport details, payroll numbers, salary and pension details, a record of sick days, certain medical information of Users)
  * Details of transactions made by you through the Website
  * Responses to optional research surveys we ask you or Users to complete
  * Details of your or your Users’ visits to our Website, which includes without limitation location and traffic data, weblogs, resources you access and other communication data.

As you will be submitting and providing Client Data which may contain the personal data (and potentially sensitive personal data (as such terms are defined under the Act)) of Users and third parties, you acknowledge and accept that you are solely responsible for obtaining all required consents, authorisations and permissions from such Users and third parties to enable you to provide such information to us and to grant to us the rights set forth in this privacy policy and the EULA. It is your responsibility to ensure that all such Users and third parties are aware of and accept the terms of this privacy policy and that you have obtained explicit consent of Users to our processing any of their sensitive personal data in accordance with this privacy policy and the EULA. You may not provide us with any Client Data or other information containing personal data of Users or third parties unless and until you have obtained all necessary consents, authorisations and permissions to do so. You and we intend that, in relation to Client Data, you will be the data controller and we will be a data processor.

You acknowledge and agree that we cannot be held responsible any unauthorised access or accidental loss, damage, corruption or disclosure of Client Data arising from or in connection with your use or disclosure of Client Data. You agree to indemnify us in accordance with Clause 14 of the EULA for any claims made by any Users arising from any unauthorised access or accidental loss, damage, corruption or disclosure of Client Data arising from or in connection with your use or disclosure of Client Data.

COOKIES AND IP ADDRESSES

We may obtain information about your and your Users’ computer, which includes your and your Users’ IP address, browser type and operating system where available. This accumulation of data is used to assist system administration, and to supply information to our advertisers. The collection of this data does not identify any personal data about you or your Users.

We may also collect information regarding your or your Users’ browsing activity and interests through use of a cookie file. This cookie file is stored on the hard drive of your or your Users’ computer, and contains information that is transferred to your or your Users’ computer's hard drive. We use the collection of this data to help us improve the experience of users on our Website and Service, and to deliver a more personalised service with more relevant content. The collection of this data allows us to:

  * Store data indicative of your or your Users’ preferences, allowing us to adjust our Website to appeal to your individual interests
  * Estimate the size and usage patterns of our audience
  * Record the details of any transactions carried out by you through our Website
  * Identify you or your Users upon your/their return to our Website
  * Increase the speed of your or your Users’ searches

We use the following cookies:

  * **Strictly necessary cookies**. These are cookies that are required for the operation of our Website and Service. They include, for example, cookies that enable you or your Users to log into secure areas of our Website or Service.

  * **Analytical/performance cookies.** They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our Website and Service when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our Website and Service works.

  * **Functionality cookies.** These are used to recognise you and your Users when you/they return to our Website. This enables us to personalise our content for you and your Users, greet you and your Users by name and remember your/their preferences.

  * **Targeting cookies.** These cookies record your and your Users’ visit to our Website, the pages you and your Users have visited and the links you and your Users have followed. We will use this information to make our Website and the advertising displayed on it (if any) more relevant to your and your Users’ interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

You can find more information about some of the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them below:

**Example of cookies used by the Service**

**Tool**

| 

**Cookie Purposes**  
  
---|---  
  
Google Analytics

| 

We use Google Analytics to collect information about how visitors use the Site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. For more information about Google’s privacy policy, please visit http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/ If you do not wish to allow the use of Google Analytics cookies at all, Google provides an opt-out plug-in for most common website browsers http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout  
  
GoSquared

| 

We use GoSquared to collect information about how visitors use the Site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. For more information about GoSquared’s privacy policy, please visit https://www.gosquared.com/legal/privacy/statement/  
  
Mixpanel

| 

We use Mixpanel to collect information about how visitors use the Site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. For more information about Mixpanel’s privacy policy, please visit https://mixpanel.com/privacy. Mixpanel provides an opt out service, which can be found here https://mixpanel.com/optout/  
  
|   
  
Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies. You and your Users remain entitled to refuse cookies by adjusting your browser settings accordingly. Doing so however may restrict your and your Users’ access to certain areas within our Website or Service. Unless you or your Users adjust your/their browser settings to refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you/they log on to our Website.

WHERE WE STORE PERSONAL DATA ABOUT YOU

The information we obtain from you and your Users (including, without limitation, Client Data) may be moved to and stored at a destination within the European Economic Area (" **EEA** "). Staff members operating within the EEA who work for or on behalf of us may process this information. Such staff members may, among other things, be involved in the processing of payment details, the provision of support services and the delivery of your and your Users’ request(s) for us to provide services. When submitting your and your Users’ personal data, you are agreeing to such processing, transfer or storage as outlined above. We will ensure at all times to take all reasonable steps necessary to maintain the security of your data in accordance with this privacy policy.

Without limiting the foregoing, you agree that the information we obtain from you and your Users (including, without limitation, Client Data) may be processed by our service providers based in, countries outside of the EEA for the purposes of providing you with the Service. Such countries do not always provide the same level of data protection as the UK; however where such transfers of data occur, we do put in place contracts that include security obligations on our service providers to ensure that your and your Users’ personal data is protected in accordance with UK standards.

We store the data you and your Users provide us with on our secure servers. In the event of us giving you or your Users (or you/they choosing) a password which grants you/them access to specific areas within our Website or Service, it remains your/their responsibility to maintain the confidentiality of this password. This includes the responsibility to refrain from sharing your/their password with other parties.

Because the transmission of data via the Internet cannot be assumed completely secure, we cannot guarantee the security of any of your or your Users’ data transmitted to our Website or Service; you are therefore responsible for any risk associated with such transmission. We will however at all times take all reasonable steps to ensure the transmission of your and your Users’ data is executed as securely as possible, and upon receipt of your/their data we will continue at all times to enforce strict security procedures and features in an attempt to prevent any unauthorised access.

HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

The information we hold about you and your Users may be used in any of the following ways:

  * To provide you and your Users with the Service, including administration and management of your account
  * To allow you to upload, store and access Client Data
  * To enable Users to access certain aspects of Charlie and limited Client Data pertinent to themselves
  * To provide you and Users with user support
  * To moderate your account
  * For research and analytics purposes (for example, to improve the quality of the Service)
  * To ensure security for you, the Users, our staff and other users of the Service
  * To comply with applicable Laws, court orders, government and law enforcement agencies’ requests
  * To provide you and Users with online personalised services and targeted advertising
  * To send you further information about our services for which we think you may have an interest. This information will be supplied only where you have given consent
  * To send you further information about our services based on a request we have received from you
  * To fulfil the obligations we have in relation to any contracts we have in place with you (including, without limitation, the EULA)
  * To provide you with notification about any changes to our services

We will never supply your data to third parties unless under the conditions stated beneath this section of our policy. Notwithstanding the foregoing, we may aggregate and anonymise personal data (excluding, for the avoidance of doubt, sensitive personal data) and use and share such aggregated and anonymised personal data with third parties for statistical purposes and for the purpose of data analytics, product development, service improvement.

DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

Disclosure of your personal data (including, without limitation, Client Data) to third parties will only occur if:

  * We sell or purchase any business or assets. In such case, we may authorise the disclosure of your personal data to prospective sellers or buyers of such business or assets
  * All or the substantial majority of our assets are sold to a third party. In such case, your personal data may be one of the transferred assets
  * We are required to disclose your or your Users’ personal data in order to fulfil any legal obligation, to enforce our EULA, or to protect the property, rights or safety of Charlie, users of our services or others. In such case, information may be exchanged with third party companies or organisations in order to prevent fraud or reduce credit risk

You acknowledge and agree that we may also disclose personal data (including, without limitation, Client Data) with: (i) our service providers involved in the provision, distribution, delivery and support of the Service, including the storage of any Client Data; (ii) fraud prevention agencies; (iii) law enforcement agencies, regulators, courts and public authorities; and (iv) emergency services.

Our service providers have to follow our express instructions when processing the personal data you or your Users provide and they must comply with appropriate security measures to protect such personal data, and we do not allow them to use this information for their own commercial purposes.

YOUR RIGHTS

You retain the right to request us to refrain from processing your data for the purposes of marketing. To exercise such right, you may reply to any information we send you, detailing your request that we refrain from sending any marketing correspondence, or you can exercise this same right by contacting us electronically via email at hello@charliehr.com. If at any time we intend to use your data for such marketing purposes however, it is standard practice for us to make you aware in advance of collecting such data.

We may at times provide links on our Website to third party websites, including without limitation those owned or managed by our partner networks, affiliates or advertisers. These websites have separate privacy policies, and we therefore cannot accept any responsibility for the content. As such, choosing to follow these links is a choice you make at your own risk, and we advise that you check these websites' individual privacy policies before submitting any personal data.

ACCESSING YOUR INFORMATION

In accordance with the Act, you retain at all times the right to access any data we hold about you. You may exercise this right by making a request in accordance with the Act, and any such request may carry a £10 fee which will cover the administration costs incurred in providing you with any details of the data we hold about you.

HOW LONG WE KEEP PERSONAL DATA FOR

The periods for which we keep information depend on the purpose for which the information was collected and the use to which it is put. We will not keep personal data for longer than necessary for our business purposes or for legal requirements.

Some information such as such as the date, time and duration of your activity on Charlie, your and your Users’ phone number and IP address will be held for up to one year, for instance if this is necessary to meet our legal obligations, or is in accordance with industry practice.

CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

If at any time we make a change to our privacy policy, we will update this page to reflect such change. Where we feel it appropriate, we will notify you by email, however we recommend you review this page periodically to ensure you remain happy with the latest version.

QUESTIONS, COMMENTS AND GETTING IN TOUCH

We welcome any questions or comments in relation to this privacy policy, and advise you to send any such communication to [ team@charliehr.com ](mailto:team@charliehr.com)
